A TRIP ON THE TRUE NORTH
Li Dayu and her cousin Liu Qian were on a trip to Canada to visit their cousins in Montreal
on the Atlantic coast.
Rather than take the aeroplane all the way,
they decided to fly to Vancouver and then take the train west to east across Canada.
The thought that they could cross the whole continent was exciting.
Their friend, Danny Lin, was waiting at the airport.
On the way to the station, he chatted about their trip.
You’re going to see some great scenery.
Going eastward, you’ll pass mountains and thousands of lakes
and forests, as well as wide rivers and large cities.
Here in Vancouver, you’re in Canada’s warmest part.
People say it is Canada’s most beautiful city,
surrounded by mountains and the Pacific Ocean.
Its population is increasing rapidly.
Earlier that day, when they crossed the Rocky Mountains,
they managed to catch sight of some mountain goats and even a grizzly bear
and an eagle.
Their next stop was Calgary, which is famous for the Calgary Stampede.
Cowboys from all over the world come to compete in the Stampede.
Many of them have a gift for riding wild horses and can win thousands of dollars in prizes.
After two days’ travel, the girls began to realize that Canada is quite empty.
After dinner, they were back in an urban area,
the busy port city of Thunder Bay at the top of the Great Lakes.
The girls were surprised at the fact that ocean ships can sail up the Great Lakes.
Because of the Great Lakes, they learned,
Canada has more fresh water than any other country in the world.
In fact, it has one-third of the world’s total fresh water,
and much of it is in the Great Lakes.